It's no secret that our society has a digital device problem. 92% of Americans own a smartphone.
Researchers found that we are more connected than ever before, and yet feel more isolated, more lonely, more depressed than ever before.
How is that possible? Social scientists call this a collective action problem. We all agree that these devices are having a detrimental impact on our mental health, and yet it feels virtually impossible to withdraw from these devices because they are so interconnected in our lives. So what can we do?
Well, good morning. It's good to see all of you this morning as we continue our series on this digital fast. Last week, Pastor Michelle kicked us off. It's a four-week series where we're talking about the influence of modern technology on our spiritual lives. And as part of this series, we've invited you to participate in a 28-day digital detox. If this is your first Sunday, don't leave yet.
Give me a couple minutes. Aimed at helping us step away from the almost constant input that our phones and tablets and screens on almost every wall of our house have in our lives, for the purpose of not just fasting from screens, but for the purpose of having clearer minds so that we can establish healthier boundaries with these devices long-term.
The goal is not just a 28-day religious practice that we jump through this hoop, check the box, and say, "Oh, we can do it if we want to do it." The goal is that we would step far enough back to really understand what our relationship with our devices is.
And then we actually intentionally are going to end the series on Father's Day with an invitation to all of our families to prayerfully consider what long-term boundaries might look like moving forward. We aren't anti-technology.
I'm preaching with an iPad this morning. Work devices on work hours is a part of the fast.
So, but we are anti being conformed to the patterns of this world. And we are pro being transformed by the renewing voice of God. And I think most of us in the room know both anecdotally and through research, much of which Pastor Michelle shared with us last week, that there aren't many more effective tools at conforming us to the patterns of this world than the glowing rectangles in our pockets and the large glowing rectangles against us.
And the large glowing rectangles, again, that we hang on almost every wall in our house.
And inside your bulletin, you'll see an explanation of a few different fast options that you can choose from, one of which is totally customizable for what works for you and your family in this season of your life.
I'd love for you to prayerfully consider that. We'd also love for you to, we haven't talked much about this. There's a link there in the bulletin and on our website where you can sign up to say I'm doing some version of the fast and we're sending out weekly emails
that have a very brief survey where you can share kind of what God's been doing in your heart and in your life.
So far, we've had a number of you fill those out. I think we're probably close to saving about 100 hours last week just from the handful of people that filled out that form.
So we'd love to have you check that out with us. That's kind of the plan for the next couple weeks. Let me pray and we'll get started.
Good Shepherd.
That term comes with surrender and leadership.
Total surrender to your leadership in our lives, even when it takes us through the valley of the shadow of death.
And we, those of us who have tasted and seen your goodness, willingly surrender to that path because we know that on the other side is anointing.
We know that on the other side is a table prepared for us.
And so, God, for those of us that have surrendered to your voice as the Good Shepherd in our lives, God, renew that commitment this morning.
Remind us, show us where there are voices of leadership that are coming into our lives to distract us from the voice of the Good Shepherd.
And God, for those who have not yet tasted and seen that you are good, I pray that we would, that you by your Holy Spirit would be opening eyes.
And minds and hearts of those who have maybe been interested in a surrendered life, but hesitant to it.
Holy Spirit, have your way in this room this morning for your glory, for our good, and for the good of our neighbors.
It's in Jesus' name I pray. Amen.
All right, apple blossom was a few weeks ago, right? Some of you are pumped.
Some of you are pumped. So I'd love to see, just by a show of hands, how many of us are pro-apple blossom people in the room? We lean into it. We love it.
All right. How many of us are, "I'm gonna get out of town for a week and hope nobody's..." Okay, that's pretty evenly split.
Now here's the real test. For those of you that are pro-apple blossom, how many of you are pro-Midway?
Not a lot of pro-Midway people in the room. Okay, now I see where we're at.
If those of you that don't know, Midway is kind of that downtown walking mall. They fill with vendors on every street.
And this year, I went down to Midway for the first time in a very long time.
And I will tell you from my experience that every five steps, another vendor called out to me.
Funnel cakes, fried Oreos, fresh squeezed lemonade, Dippin' Dots, and on and on we could go.
Every vendor's voice saying the same thing. Come on over, we have what you're looking for.
The problem is that I, like most of you, have a limited budget, and even more so, a limited amount of calories that I should be intaking on any single Saturday of my life.
But, I had heard that there was one vendor, one very specific vendor, whose voice called to me from a distance, the holy grail of my fried food.
One vendor at Midway had a blooming onion. Yes. And I had decided, pre-decided before getting to Midway, that that was what I was on the hunt for.
I listened for the voice of that vendor. It wasn't that the other voices weren't attractive, they were, but I had already decided where I was headed, and thankfully so.
Because imagine, if some of you maybe even had this experience going down to Midway without a plan, and with a credit card that has no limits,
because of course the vendors now take credit cards, I would have found myself in trouble.
And I think that this is a helpful picture to have in mind as we open our Bibles to John chapter 10 this morning,
and look at it through the lens of the digital fast, because Midway is a tangible and visible expression of our daily experience in 2026.
We carry this experience in our pockets, and in our purses, and on the walls of almost every room of our house.
Voices calling out to us. Politicians, social media influencers, news feeds, podcasts, algorithms, advertisers, experts, and friends.
All calling out to us with that same voice, "Look to me, follow me, and I will lead you to life."
All of these voices are promising to add value to our lives, and the question isn't if they are speaking.
The question is how much of our time, energy, and attention are we giving to them?
Or to take it one level deeper, what voices are shaping the direction of your life?
And the secondary question behind that, what voices are leading your life?
And secondarily, what kind of a life are those voices leading you to?
These are some of the primary questions that I think Jesus is inviting us to wrestle with in John chapter 10.
And since we're on a theme of going old school, I'd love to invite you, if you're able, to stand as we read God's Word this morning.
John chapter 10, starting in verse 1, Jesus begins a proclamation with,
Truly, truly, I say to you, he who does not enter the sheepfold by the door but climbs in by another way, that man is a thief and a robber.
But he who enters by the door is the shepherd of the sheep. To him the gate opens, the sheep hear his voice, and he calls his own sheep by name and leads them out.
When he has brought out all of his own, he goes before them, and the sheep follow him, for they know his voice.
A stranger they will not follow, but they will flee from, for they do not know the voice of strangers.
This figure of speech Jesus used with them, but they did not understand what he was saying to them.
So Jesus again said to them, "Truly, truly, I say to you, I am the door of the sheep.
All who came before me are thieves and robbers, but the sheep did not listen to them.
I am the door. If anyone enters by me, he will be saved and he will go in and out and find pasture.
The thief comes only to steal, kill, and destroy. I came that they may have life and have it abundantly.
I am the good shepherd. The good shepherd lays down his life for the sheep.
He who is a hired hand and not a shepherd, who does not own the sheep, sees the wolf coming and leaves the sheep and flees, and the wolf snatches them and scatters them.
He flees because he is a hired hand and cares nothing for the sheep. I am the good shepherd.
I know my own and my own know me, just as the Father knows me, and I know the Father, and I lay down my life for the sheep.
My sheep hear my voice. I know them, and they follow me." This is the word of the Lord.
You can have a seat. See, you guys are getting there. We're figuring it out. One of these days. One of these days will be a semi-liturgical church.
The immediate context of this passage, some of you will be familiar with, is Jesus healing a blind man on the Sabbath and a group of Jewish synagogue leaders banishing
the man from the synagogue for the rest of his life and accusing Jesus of being a sinner. And this is the address that follows directly after.
These leaders in the synagogue are banishing people who are being healed by the creator of the universe
and calling the creator of the universe a sinner. And so Jesus picks up with this very culturally relevant illustration. Everybody in
and around that time would have been familiar with shepherds and sheep and sheep pens.
So he's using a relevant illustration that talks to them about the different voices that seek to influence their lives.
But it's not just a convenient cultural illustration. It's an illustration that has been developing
throughout the Hebrew Bible from its onset. This imagery of God being the shepherd of his people is well-developed in the
Scriptures of Jesus throughout this time. And so the people would know, okay, God is the shepherd, and God appoints
human leaders to shepherd his people under his leadership. God regularly refers to his people as
sheep, dependent, vulnerable, and prone to wander. And with that, we all can exhale because God knows and expects that we
are prone to wander and vulnerable and in need of his leadership. Not only that, but he knows that the leaders that he
has appointed to shepherd his people under him will fail because they themselves are sheep who are prone to wander and prone to
fall away. And so there's this regular imagery that God is the shepherd of his people, that there are people underneath him
who shepherd, but shepherd poorly. And throughout the prophets, we have this promise that one day God
himself will come and shepherd his people. And if you want some fun reading this week, I would encourage
you to read the Ezekiel chapter 34, and then side by side, read John chapter 10. Jesus is stepping into this
story, and he is accusing these Pharisees, these synagogue leaders, of being failed shepherds who are not
doing the thing that God has invited them to do, and he himself is saying, "Okay, if you're not going
to do it, I am going to fulfill my promise. I will come, and I will be the good shepherd who leads his
people to life and life more abundantly." All of that immediate context and larger biblical context
comes together in this statement from Jesus, which is rebuking the Pharisees for being failed shepherds who
have prioritized their own power and well-being over the well-being of the sheep. And I'm going to
take leadership very much this day from first century Pharisees, I am sure that we can begin to imagine some type of
leaders that might want our lives following them but don't really care about our well-being in the end. Jesus rebukes
the Pharisees who have prioritized their own power and well-being, and he actually calls them thieves and robbers. In their own
temple, in their own synagogue, he calls these leaders thieves and robbers. No wonder they're upset and
frustrated. But not only is he in many ways critiquing the Pharisees, but I think he's also secondarily inviting
the crowd around to consider what voice or voices they are trusting to lead them. And then that question
underneath the question is, "Okay, if these are the voices that are leading you, what type of life is the
outcome of their leadership for you?" These central questions are addressed throughout the
John chapter 10, but most clearly in the famous chapter 10, verse 10, and that's where I want to spend the
majority of our time this morning. "The thief comes only to steal and kill and destroy. I have come
that the sheep may have life and have it abundantly." In this passage, we have two voices
and two types of life that result in those voices giving leadership to our lives. The first voice is
that of the thief. And again, in the immediate context, Jesus is clearly referring to the failed
religious leaders of Israel, but in verse 10, he transitions. Earlier in the passage, he calls them
all of these failed leaders, thieves and robbers. But in verse 10, he transitions from a plural, thieves and robbers,
to a singular thief, almost to indicate that there are any number of harmful and self-centered voices
who seek to lead God's people away from God's plan for their lives. And every voice of the thief fits
into the category that can be traced back to the original thief in the garden, the enemy of God who
comes and whispers an alternative voice of leadership in the lives of God's people. The voice of the thief
always competes with God's voice, and it always promises life and flourishing apart from a
surrendered obedience to God. And again, I don't think many of us are being discipled by
first-century Pharisees, but we are being discipled by thousands of voices that are
competing for influence and leadership in our lives apart from God. And they come
primarily in our cultural context to us through our phones and our pockets and the
screens on most walls in our homes. They come in the forms of politicians,
influencers, news outlets, podcasts, algorithms, experts, and mindless entertainment. And
at the end of the day, they are like hired hands. They do not really care about your
well-being. Their primary motivation is their own status, wealth, influence, and
success. And whether they intend for it to happen or not, many of these voices have
good intentions. But if they don't know the voice of the Father and they're
offering leadership to the Father's sheep, they will lead us astray. And
whether they intend to or not, the life that results in us placing the
leadership of our lives in the hands of anyone other than the Good Shepherd is
it will lead to our lives being stolen, killed, and destroyed. This is the
result. This is what's at stake when we offer the leadership of our lives to
anyone other than the Good Shepherd. The Greek for steel here is klepto. Okay, I
think we can get there, right? And it carries the weight of being secretly stolen
from. And so there's a part of this, I think, when we apply it to the digital
fast in our lives, there is a number of voices and motivation behind the voices
and technology and algorithms that are not outright up in our faces
stealing from us, but they are secretly stealing from us. It's not always
obvious. It's often subtle, and it happens slowly over time, 10 minutes here,
20 minutes there, and maybe, if we're willing to admit, one four-hour binge
session on a Friday evening. All right, that's just me. Okay, you guys are holy.
That's great. It's happening slowly over time. Many studies indicate that our
attention spans are down to around 45 seconds. We do not know how to sit still, be
quiet, and listen for the voice of God in our lives. The thief comes to secretly steal
from us. Many of us spend more time interacting with the screen than any other
person in our life. Who are we willingly giving the leadership of our lives over
to? Not only does the thief come to steal, but also to kill. This Greek word is often
used when sacrifices are being made or when animals are being killed for the sake of
making a meal. These animals ultimately are being consumed for the purpose of the
person doing the killing. Again, let's sit with this and apply this to the voices that
come to us through technology. We are being consumed. We are the sacrifice on
the altar of the success and wealth of the voices that we are giving our
leadership over to. Many of these voices are intentionally consuming our time and
attention for their own personal gain. Many of these voices know that it is killing us, and
not only do they not do anything about it, but they are secretly improving their
ability to sacrifice us on the altar of their own wealth, success, and power. The
tech industry is running the same playbook that the cigarette companies did in the
'70s and the sugar companies did in the early 2000s. They have power, wealth, and
influence. They know it's killing us, and they are doing everything they can to hide the
fact from us that it is killing us so that they can continue to profit and gain from
our being sacrificed or consumed. The thief comes to steal and to kill. Many of the
people, many of the people who designed the technology pumping these voices into
our pockets, have strict limits on their own family usage of these products. Which
makes me wonder, if the shepherds of Silicon Valley won't let their own sheep
graze freely in these pastures, maybe we should more carefully consider our own
grazing habits. One tech leader in the documentary The Social Dilemma put it this
way. He said, "There's only one other industry that calls their consumers users, and
it's illegal drug dealers. The voices that we are allowing to pump into our
pockets and on our walls to have leadership over the direction of our lives
consider you the product that they are willing to sacrifice on the altar of
their own productivity, of their own wealth, of their own status. The thief comes
only to steal and to kill and to destroy." And when I was studying this
passage in the English, I was like, "Oh, it's like classic pastor move. You just use
three words. The third word is more of just the synonym for kill. Like, I get
it. Adds to the effect. But as you look at the Greek, the word destroy is not just
a synonym for kill, but it actually, it comes with the idea of rendering
something useless. This word is often used when things are lost. Think
about the parable of the lost coin. When a woman loses a coin,
this coin is the same Greek word for destroy. Ultimately, the coin exists.
It's there. It has value if it can be found. But as long as it
can't be found, there's no value to it. The coin is rendered useless.
And the reality is if these voices don't kill us, they will
likely render our lives useless. Depression often quickly follows a
life that feels like it has no purpose. I'm getting to the age where a
lot of my friends are having this conversation about a midlife
crisis. Anybody? Anybody? Okay, good. None of us are having
midlife crisis. None of us are buying cars that we used to drive when
we were kids or getting motorcycles when we shouldn't have them. None of us?
Okay. All right. Again, just me. You guys are holy. That's great and awesome.
But these midlife crises, what happens is we look back at the purpose and the
productivity of our lives, and we think, huh, is my life as meaningful
and filled with purpose as I think it was? The thief comes to render
our lives useless, that we have no purpose. There are literally millions
of voices operating under the category of thief, and we are giving
them our time and attention at unprecedented rates, and it is
rendering our lives useless for the kingdom of God. Not in your face.
Not, "Look, I'm the thief. I'm here to render your life useless."
That's not how it works. It happens subtly over time, and before we know it,
we make statements about how busy our lives are, and how packed our schedules
are, and how we can't possibly do the Christian charity for the neighbor next
door because we just don't have the time and the capacity, and I'm just
wondering, is it possible that we have far more time, availability, and
willingness to participate in God's kingdom if we put a little bit of
restriction on the screens in our pockets and on the walls of our homes?
One person filled out the survey this week, and they said something
around the lines of, "What are you learning most in this fast?" and they
said something along the lines of, "I am realizing that when I say the
phrase, 'I don't have time,' I have the time." The thief subtly comes to steal,
kill, and render our lives useless. Have I sufficiently unpacked the bad news this
morning for us? If you want more bad news, you know, just watch the Social Dilemma, and
that'll get your fix. But for now, let's transition a little bit to the good news.
The good news is God has fulfilled his promise that he gave to the prophets. He
himself has come as the one good true shepherd to lead not only the lost sheep
of Israel, which is the primary context in John 10, but he goes on to say, "I have
other sheep and another flock that I have come to lead away from the voices of
leadership that lead to their killing, stealing, and destroying. I'm rebuking
the Pharisees, the false religious leaders of Israel, and I'm also coming for a
whole other flock of people from every tribe, language, nation, and tongue who
might not have Pharisee religious leaders sent by me, but they have
people who are providing voices of leadership to their life, and I am
coming to get them and bring them out into a life that is abundant and
flourishing. The good news is God has fulfilled his promise. Jesus is the
good shepherd who lays down his life for the sheep. Jesus has come to lead
us away from the nefarious leaders, religious, political, and secular who are
seeking to lead us away from his kingdom for their own personal gain. And
again, I don't want to be too, like, anti-anybody other than God. There are
many wonderful people with wonderful motivations who are trying to lead us to
a life of meaning and purpose, but if they don't know the voice of the good
shepherd, ultimately they are leading us to a life of less value than
that of a life placed in the voice of the good shepherd. The good
shepherd knows his sheep. He calls his sheep by name. He leads his sheep, protects
his sheep, and sacrificially lays down his life for them. The thief comes to
steal, to kill and destroy. The good shepherd comes to give life, and life more abundantly.
The thief knows you by demographic. The thief knows you. They have an algorithm
built for you based on the demographic of your life, but the good shepherd knows your
name. He knit you together in your mother's womb. He knows the hairs on your
head. He knows you. The thief steals. The good shepherd gives. The thief
sacrifices. The good shepherd is sacrificed for us. The thief renders your
life useless. The good shepherd invites you into an abundant life with
eternal significance. These are the voices that Jesus is putting
before us to consider. There are thieves and robbers all around who are calling
your name, offering you all kinds of promises on the other side of you, giving
more of your leadership over to their lives. And Jesus, the good shepherd,
who made you, is inviting you to listen and obey his. And the result is abundant life.
And this abundant life is not always easy or comfortable. It often requires us
willingly following our shepherd through the valley of the shadow of death.
But it is always worth it. Many of the voices in our pockets promise abundant, flourishing life
with next to no sacrifice, next to no hardship. Just do this thing, and then over the next 30 days, you'll
get this, whatever it might be. Jesus doesn't give us these easy promises. He says, "Come, take up your cross
and follow me." But on the other side of laying down our life for his leadership is abundant life and
flourishing, eternal life that starts now. If you want a life with purpose and meaning, you follow the
one who made you and who knows what he created you for. It is a great adventure. It is an invitation to
build a kingdom that will last forever. My main point for this morning is pretty simple. Every voice promises
life, but only one leads to it. This is Jesus' invitation in John chapter 10. There are a number of voices in
your life that will promise life, but only one will lead you to the life that you were made for. The question
for us then becomes, do we hear the voice of Jesus? This is a question that I have been wrestling with for the past week.
My sheep hear my voice. They know my voice and they follow it. I am a pastor who studies the Scriptures
on a regular basis. I know theology. I understand how to study Scripture, but that's not the question.
The question is not, did you grow up in church? Have you been baptized? The question is not, do you know
the creeds and do you know what you believe intellectually? The question for us becomes,
do you hear the voice of the Good Shepherd? And that's a far different question than do you have
good theology, than do you do good things? It's a significant question that we need to really sit
with this morning, is do we hear the voice of Jesus, and do we listen to it? My sheep hear my voice,
I know them, and they follow me.
Is it possible that we've so allowed our lives to be filled with voices of thieves and robbers,
that Jesus is speaking, and we can't hear him over the noise?
Again, the goal of the digital fast is not simply less screen time.
The goal is to make more room for the voice of the Good Shepherd in your life.
Because sheep learn the voice of the shepherd through relationship and proximity.
And my fear is that we have far more relationship and proximity with the voice of thieves and robbers than we do with the voice of Jesus.
The last thing I want for this 28-day fast is for it to be a religious hoop that we jump through to make us feel better about ourselves.
I want it to be us reclaiming our relationship with the voices in our lives.
Not all voices on our phone are bad. Not all voices on TV screens are bad. It's not about that.
Ultimately, establishing healthy boundaries where we have more time to sit in the presence of the Good Shepherd and hear His voice.
And it's not easy, and it's not always the most comfortable. I would much rather put AirPods in my ears and listen to a podcast when I go on a drive than sit and listen to the voice of God.
And that's coming from a guy who's being ordained tonight.
This is a hard truth. And in our cultural moment today,
it's so easy to not even realize how much more time and energy we are giving to other voices in our life than the voice of Jesus.
I'd love to give just a really practical tip for this week.
Again, kicking it old school. Thanks, Ballinger, for kicking us off that way.
I feel like for me, I don't know about for you, a lot of times some of that really bad scrolling,
that binge watching, it happens late at night when we're tired and things have been hard,
and we just want to kick back and veg out. I'd encourage you this week to maybe consider at nighttime
putting the phone away and following the prayer of examine from St. Ignatius.
And you can find information about that on the internet, but it's really just this time to end your day with self-reflection,
inviting the voice of the Good Shepherd to offer guidance in your life.
Where, God, were you present in my life this week, this day?
What brought me life today? What diminished life? What stole and killed and destroyed my life today?
What voices was I listening to? And where were you inviting me into deeper communion
that I either stepped into or missed the opportunity to step into?
And the beautiful thing about, you read Saint Ignatius, is the goal of this is not guilt.
The goal of this is not to go back through your day and feel bad about how much you blew it.
The goal of it is to realize how much God was inviting you into throughout the day.
And to wake up the next morning with fresh eyes and open ears to hear what he might have for us the next day.
Again, at night, examine your life and realize how many times you miss the voice of God and not feel guilty or shame,
but feel the kindness of the Lord who continues to speak to us even when we fail.
Really, to me, that's the most beautiful thing about the rebuke of the Pharisees throughout Jesus' ministry,
is he's just pursuing them.
He so desperately wants them to see where they're missing the mark.
He weeps over the people.
He spends so much of his time with the Pharisees because they're so close to getting it,
that they just can't hear the voice of the Good Shepherd when he speaks to them.
What if we started a new practice at night where we invited God to reveal to us where he was speaking and where we missed him,
and to receive that with grace and step into the next day with open eyes and open ears?
I have been told by many teachers of preaching classes that the best sermons end where they started.
I don't know how good I feel about likening the voice of the Good Shepherd to a $15 bloomin' onion.
But I think we get the point. The point is our lives are filled with competing voices.
All over the place. Every step we take, there is another voice calling out to us, inviting us to receive their leadership.
But for those of us who are followers of Jesus, there is a singular voice that leads us out,
goes before us, and shows us a better way to live.
A way that leads to abundant life.
I'm going to pray, and we're going to end with communion this morning.
So as I pray, or before or after, whatever, if you haven't had time to grab a communion cup at the back table, I'd invite you to do that.
Let's pray, and then we'll transition to that.
Father, Good Shepherd,
we thank you for the leadership you give to us.
You don't just tell us where to go, you go before us.
You go before us, and you show us that on the other side of sacrificial death is resurrection life.
So God, I just pray now for all of us that are bombarded with voices all over our lives, all over our...
Every step we take, there's another voice calling out to us.
I pray this morning that we would be reminded that there is one voice above all other voices that knows us by name, that is inviting us to follow.
You are inviting us to follow you.
Give us ears to hear that voice and feet to obey that voice.
Make us aware of where other voices are stealing and killing and rendering our lives useless.
In Jesus' name, I pray. Amen.
Well, as we end, I do want to create some intentional space for us to sit in quiet and listen to the voice of God
who lays down his life so that we can experience abundant life.
Again, every preaching lesson I hear talks about ending the sermon where you started.
Every good church leadership lesson I hear says, "Don't give people too much silence."
But we're breaking the rules today.
So I'm just going to give us just three to five minutes of silence,
which is going to feel like 10 to 15 minutes of silence in this room.
And I just invite you to ask the Holy Spirit to awaken the voice of the Good Shepherd in your life,
to give you invitation, to give you encouragement,
to give you conviction that leads to obedience, not out of shame,
but out of a graceful surrender.
We'll just sit for a minute or two, Dave, we'll keep playing, and just listen for the voice of the Good Shepherd in our lives,
and then we'll take communion together.